Wrege, Charles D. Collection of Midvale Steel Company Photographic Negatives 6013 P
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Charles D. Wrege Collection of Midvale Steel Company Photographic Negatives
1930-1954
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Wrege, Charles D.
6013 P
0.58 cubic feet
0.6 linear ft.
Photographic negatives.
Negatives of the Midvale Company, 1930-1954, showing steel processes and employees at work.
5758043
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, January 30, 2013
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 17, 2016
Biographical / Historical
Charles "Chuck" Wrege finished his undergraduate degree in Upsala College, obtained his Masters degree at the New School fo Social Research and another Masters of Business Administration and his Ph.D. at NYU. He taught industrial management at Rutgers University for 30 years. He became a renowned historian, researcher and writer. He is regarded as a "National Treasure" by many in his field because of his expertise and the seminal research he has done in the area of management history.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5167: Charles D. Wrege Hawthorne Studies Research Data 5618: Charles D. Wrege Research Papers Regarding History of Management 5618 P: Charles D. Wrege History of Management Collection of Midvale Steel Company Photographs 6012 AV: Charles D. Wrege Collection of Audio-Visual Materials 6012m: Charles D. Wrege "Facts and Fallacies of Hawthorne" Doctoral Dissertation. 1961 6014: Charles D. Wrege Collection of History of Management Documents 6014 P: Charles D. Wrege Collection of History of Management Photographs 6054: Charles D. Wrege Collection of Additional Taylor Charts 6271: Charles D. Wrege Collection of International Management Institute Correspondence 6304: Charles Wrege Collection of Midvale Steel Company Index Cards
Wrege, Charles D.; Midvale Steel Company --Archives
5758043
- Midvale Corporation. Philadelphia, Pa (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  #000 - 1 photograph
- Industrial lighting advertisements. 1926 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  #000
- Midvale Corporation (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Men working on lower cross head support beam -- #414
- Employee #510-323T - Working on roll with sleeve for U.S. Steel Co. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  #6
- #19 Press and men operating manipulator, January 23, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  #10A
- Operator Roma performing supersonic testing - January 23, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  #12A - 1 photograph
- Employees watching billet for General Electric Company, coming out of Heating Furnace #2 press - January 27, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  #16A
- Gear Band for Delaval Co. - machinist, inside ring - Malkowski; Helper, outside ring - Fioravanti -- January 28, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  #20A
- Scarfing - February 2, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  #26
- Layout of #4 - February 5, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  #36B - 1 photograph
- 280 mm shell and employees at #16 press - February 13, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  #46B
- Employee Herman Brock at 60" lathe, #4 machine shop - February 16, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  #48A
- Riggero and Rotor - 3/16/1953 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  #74
- Burning Loewy plate no. B1480? (Box 1, Folder 14)
  #81 - 1 photograph
- Worker checking machine a lathe? (Box 1, Folder 15)
  #82
- #7 Hammer gang - March 25, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  #84A - 1 photograph
- Member 7 steam hammer gang - March 25, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  #84B - -2 photographs
- Grant heat - (Box 1, Folder 18)
  #96
- Easter baskets - April 3, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  #89A
- 3rd Cast Steel pour - April 13, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  #97
- Samuel Wattz, Jr., Trepanning Lathe - April 14, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  #99B
- Visit of School Teachers (Teachers at furnace) - April 15, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  #101
- Richard, Nalle & Ed Murphy - April 27, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  #103
- Group from NATO greeted by Richard Nalle, President, Midvale Corporation at Main Office Building - May 13, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  #113A -- 2 photographs
- Machinist - Ruthkowski and Foreman Platka at machine - May 29, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  #130A
- Albert McDonald at 50 ton furnace - June 19, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  #147A - a photograph
- Workers Peter Cardmore (first helper) and Joseph Haslam (second helper) at 50 ton furnace - July 19, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  #147B
- Signing A.F.L. Agreement - June 20, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  #162 -- 1 photograph
- Workers creating makeshift ramp (Box 1, Folder 29)
  #174 -- 1 photograph
- Workers working with hot metal (Box 1, Folder 30)
  #176 -- 2 photographs
- Heat induction test by Scanlon - August 24, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  #180 -- 1 photograph
- Blood Donation (Box 1, Folder 32)
  #194 D&G -- 2 photographs
- Lower crosshead beam plate for the Loewy Hydro press Company, part of U.S. Air force, heavy metal program -- 4/16/1954 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  #212A -- 1 photograph
- Neg #224 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  #224 -- 1 photograph
- Thanksgiving baskets for F.L.U. -- November 11, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  #225A
- Employee L 239-017, inspecting rings for Westinghouse - December 11, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  #233C
- Employee Newton Dyson checking lathe - December 14, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  #236
- Welding in #9 shop tool room - December, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  #245A
- Skinning plate in #9 shop, December, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  #245B
- Union Meeting, Mr. Deva and others, January 19, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  #256
- Close up of Lombardie, January 28, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  #260 -- 1 photograph
- Employee Henry Moore checking intermediate shaft for S. Morgan Smith Company, march 17, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  #290A
- Magnet #3 in open hearth stock yard (Main Office in background); Harry Johnson in car, Seigfried operating crane, April 8, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  #284A
- #19 Press, John Murtha, with calliper (Box 1, Folder 44)
  #287A
- #19 Press, C.R. Smith, pyrometer, April 8, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  #287B
- CR Smith Pyrometer, John Murtha with calliper (Driver); Schram & Joseph Hall (colored (sic)) at levers, April 8, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  #287C
- Charles Neg operating manipulator to remove (?) from #19 press, April 8, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  #288
- Operator, Mike Gresh, opening door of furnace in Open Hearth Department, April 8, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  #289
- Mrs. St. Clair greeting her father, William McCooley, engineer of #47 locomotive, July 1, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  #313A
- Mrs. St. Clair greeting her father Wm. MColey, Engineer #47 locomotive for Midvale yards, July 1, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  #313B
- John Mudd, photographer for Midvale Company, July 7, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  #316
- Signing A.F.L. Agreement, July 30, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  #323
- No information (Box 1, Folder 53)
  #324A - 1 photograph
- Erecting Philadelphia (?) Sign for The Midvale Company, September 23, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  #326
- Loading 280mm shell in #7 machine shop - 1954 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  #330A
- Presenting photo contest awards - 1954 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  #333
- Employee Joseph A. Prim with chains used to lift forgings at furnaces, November 5, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  #338
- Floormen Group, #30TP, November 8, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  #342A
- Two operators opening 50 ton ladle to pour molten steel, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  #388
- miss Fraelieb at file cabinet Main Office, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  #398
- Large Roll is Reynolds metal Co. order #54022 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  #401C
- Presentation of Watch to Mewodowski of Lower Machine Shop, December 31, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  #412
- Pouring #100 Ajax - October, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  #473
- McAvally stirring #100 Ajx furnace -- October, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  #474
- McAnally stirring #100 Ajax Furnace, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  #476
- Two Riggers Tying Knot, October 20, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  #485
- Inspecting Bar Steel, October, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  #490
- Inspecting Bar Steel, October, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  #495
- machinist Allen in #2 machine Shop, July, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  #598
- Charles Hall, Press Driver or Steam Hammer #6, February 5, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  #652
- Sunshine on molds in steel foundry, March, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  #682
- Sebastian Budgmiski on lathe, April 20, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  #689
- Man putting template on tire, July, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  #693
- mechanic Larson, medium grindings on Noton machine Roll for Thomas Steel, July, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  #695
- Machinist at grinder, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  #696
- Straightening bucket wheel on steam hammer, August, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 76)
  #702
- Frank Meroddi cleaning covers, August, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  #705
- 4 men on tongs in Smith Shop, August, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  #713
- Tracklayers at G.P. Annex, August, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 79)
  #715
- Smith Shop views, August, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 80)
  #719
- Loading billets, August, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 81)
  #722
- Loading billets, August, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 82)
  #724
- negative #734 (Box 1, Folder 83)
- Photos of locomotive #15 in yard. Ca. 1932? (Box 1, Folder 84)
  #735
- Photo of locomotive #15 in yard, ca. 1932 (Box 1, Folder 85)
  #736
- Giant press (by United) (Box 1, Folder 86)
  #1331C -- 1 photograph
- Cover for Midvale Steel Bulletin, December, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 87)
  #1543
- Employee F.M. Borek, measuring to .040 on top of machine R2126, August 9, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 88)
  #1548A
- Operator 211-181, O Seibold, fitting revolving center for lathes, August 9, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 89)
  #1549
- Fitting revolving center for lathes (Box 1, Folder 90)
  #1550
- J. Olsen, laying out tool post step rings for Navy unit, August 17, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 91)
  #1550 -- 1 photograph
- Operator H. Hansen, #211-131, checking Johannson Blocks Gauge for 14" H.C. shell thread bore base end - #2 ton room - August 17, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 92)
  #1552
- Measuring equipment (Box 1, Folder 93)
  #1553
- Soft ball game between forge and yard, September 15, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 94)
  #1559AB - 4 photographs
- Tapping - #13 furnace, open hearth, September 21, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 95)
  #1562
- Open Hearth - 100 Ton Ladle - September 22, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 96)
  #1566
- Open Hearth - 100 Ton Ladle - September 9, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 97)
  #1569
- 3rd, War Bond Rally - September 28, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 98)
  #1572+
- William Thorpe, operating new machine, making 6 thread Acme Hobs of Midvale #26 for #6 S.S. - October 6, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 99)
  #1573A
- Operator William Thorpe, #211-122, operating new machine R-3812, #2 tool room, making 6 thread Acme Hobs, made of Midvale #26 steel for #65:S. Used for threading 6" shells - October 6, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 100)
  #1573B
- Operator William Thorpe, #211-122.--October 6, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 101)
  #1574 - 1 photograph
- Conning Tower Tube for Brooklyn Navy Yard October 6, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 102)
  #1575 - 1 photograph
- Safety week - Rally at stores building, Mayor Samuels of Philadelphia speaking - May 12, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 103)
  #1588
- Safety Sign for engine machinists - June 1, 1943-May 31, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 104)
  #1593
- Safety flag presentation at stores building - July 25, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 105)
  #1594
- Personal Picnic at "Mudd's' home in New Jersey - August 12, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 106)
  #1596 - 1 photograph
- Softball teams, Wood floor Dept., playing against Forge Dept., Fern Hill Park - September 18, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 107)
  #1598 - 1 photograph
- Motive Power Repair Crew - 1951 (Box 1, Folder 108)
  #1599A
- Repairing Diesel Locomotive #39 - 1951 (Box 1, Folder 109)
  #1599B
- Fire in #2 Press plant 9:30 A.M. - September 28, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 110)
  #1599C
- 5 Star Navy "E" ceremony - 4 P.M. - October 4, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 111)
  #1600 - 1 photograph
- Midvale mascot Dog "Nellie"; Guards and Employees at Roberts Ave. entrance gate on North end of plant - October 24, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 112)
  #1601 - 1 photograph
- Bricklayer at oil heating furnace in #4 machine shop - May 31, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 113)
  #1603B
- 6th War Bond Drive by employees of #3 Open Hearth Dept. - December 5, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 114)
  #1609 - 1 photograph
- mail delivery boys before Midvale Main Office - 3/20/1945 (Box 1, Folder 115)
  #1613 - 1 photograph
- Gallagher and six girls in #7 war loan drive - April 10, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 116)
  #1614
- Pouring into pots - April 13, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 117)
  #1615 - 1 photograph
- Skinning Armor Billett - July 11, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 118)
  #1619 - 1 photograph
- Skinning Armor Billett - July 11, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 119)
  #1620
- Operator R. Fraser (Burner) - July 12, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 120)
  #1622A
- Employees William Hall and H. Gribben, burning of ends of Navy rockets - July 12, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 121)
  #1623 - 2 photographs
- Operator Joseph Bono and (?) Loftus - scaling armor with torch - July 13, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 122)
  #1624 - 1 photograph
- Employee Michael Passamonte - clipping scale of armor - July 13, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 123)
  #1625A
- Guiding armor billet ATP - July 13, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 124)
  #1626 -- 1 photograph
- Men listening to Deversa after calling them out to strike - August 20, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 125)
  #1631
- Group at opening of Co-op Lunch Room - April 23, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 126)
  #1634
- Men at electric furnace - April 30, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 127)
  #1635A
- Men at electric furnace - April 30, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 128)
  #1635B
- Men at electric furnace - April 30, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 129)
  #635C
- Men at electric furnace - April 30, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 130)
  #1635D
- Electric furnace (Box 1, Folder 131)
  #1635X
- Employee Hugh Crawford in Scottish kilt, taken in his backyard - May 2, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 132)
  #1636 -- 3 photographs
- Cutting Armor plate, Employee Elmer Drey - May 9, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 133)
  #1637 - 1 photograph
- Boring test in Armor plate - May 9, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 134)
  #1638
- Midvale trucks and men drivers - May 13, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 135)
  #1640
- Magnetic crane in ATP - May 13, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 136)
  #1643 - 1 photograph
- Operator E. J. Hughes, cutting scrap ends in ATP - May 13, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 137)
  #1644 - 1 photograph
- Employees L. Krout and J. Burg - cutting rack segment - May 13, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 138)
  #1645B - 1 photograph
- Cutting rack segment, Employee, J. Burg - May 13, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 139)
  #1645A
- Safety group and Red Cross Group at Main Office - May 15, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 140)
  #1647
- Operator Machion - unloading charcoal at open hearth furnace yard - July 1, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 141)
  #1649
- Midvale employees and at ship wharf, Philadelphia, PA - July 1, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 142)
  #1652
- Iron workers at Midvale Open Hearth - July 2, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 143)
  #1656 - 1 photograph
- Pipefitter checking pipe in underground box -- July 2, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 144)
  #1657
- First heat in new Ajax furnace in foundry, 1 P.M. - July 3, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 145)
  #1659
- First heat of new Ajax furnace in foundry, 1 P.M. - July 3, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 146)
  #1659 - 1 photograph
- Pouring into pots - 1946 (Box 1, Folder 147)
  #1660A
- Ajax Furnace - 1946 (Box 1, Folder 148)
  #1661A - 1 photograph
- Operator - Holowicz, operating I-455 machine in #7 machine shop - July 10, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 149)
  #1663
- Employee Tucker - showing correct way to use set calipers - July 10, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 150)
  #1664 - 2 photographs
- Employee using scleroscope on #2 mirror finish roll in #7 machine shop - July 10, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 151)
  #166b
- Carballoi grinders - April, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 152)
  #1671
- Employees terpier and Newt Da Hann showing method of safely using alligator shears - 1947 (Box 1, Folder 153)
  #1677
- Electric furnace gang - December, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 154)
  #1683
- Correct way of holding PEG on #7 steam hammer - December 8, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 155)
  #1687B
- Correct method of holding pin on steam hammer - December 8, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 156)
  #1687A
- Cold draw for lantern slides, Grant Mulchlitz, employee - January, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 157)
  #1696
- Fred Morton and H. Gilmore and members of Lower machine - Shop Safety Committee January 12, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 158)
  #1705
- Treatment Department Basketball team - January 15, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 159)
  #1706A
- Treatment (?) Basket Ball Team - F.A. Kraft throwing up the ball - January 15, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 160)
  #1706B
- Electric Furnace Department Basketball Team - January 29, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 161)
  #1711
- Open Hearth View - Feb. 1948 (Box 1, Folder 162)
  #1713 - 1 photograph
- Shoveling coal, open hearth - February, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 163)
  #1713A - 1 photograph
- Open hearth - view of shoveling - February, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 164)
  #1713B - 1 photograph
- Loading furnace (Box 1, Folder 165)
  #1715 - 1 photograph
- Cylinder for carbide & carbon with Ben Moore & helper - March 5, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 166)
  #1725
- Cylinder for carbide & carbon company, Ben Moore, employee - March 5, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 167)
  #1725B
- Employees of Roll tuning Shop - March 12, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 168)
  #1730
- Hooks for Crue Steel - March 23 ,1948 (Box 1, Folder 169)
  #1731
- Top E Frame for Westinghouse Company, order D56-751; Operator 270-028, James Ferguson - April 20, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 170)
  #1733
- Lawrence Kennedy (with safety glasses) Grendize hooks for removing billets from furnaces - April 20, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 171)
  #1734A
- Employees, Walter Kerby, Lawrence Kennedy and Raymond McConkey, making hooks for removing billets from furnaces - April 20, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 172)
  #1734B
- Employee Ben Longbottom, checking dimension of roll for the Armstrong Cork Company - April 20, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 173)
  #1735
- Main Office Basketball team - April 22, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 174)
  #1736
- Employee with burning equipment for skinning billets - Spring, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 175)
  #1734
- Award of Suggestion Prize to Robert Penman for best slogan; L-R Midvale employees Doyle, Hamilton, Penman & William Andersen - May 20, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 176)
  #1740
- Employees in cleaning room of steel foundry - May 21, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 177)
  #1744
- Birds eye view of Midvale Company Steel worker from roof of main office, looking North - 9/1/1948 (Box 1, Folder 178)
  #1779
- Birds eye view of Midvale Company Steel works from roof of Main Office looking North - September 1, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 179)
  #1779A
- Birds eye view of Midvale Company Steel works from roof of Main Office building looking North - September 1, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 180)
  #1779B
- Birds eye view of Midvale Company Steel works from roof of Main Office building looking North - September 1, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 181)
  #1779C
- Works from top of Main Office building on Wissahickon Avenue, looking North - 1952 (Box 1, Folder 182)
  #1779X
- Bird's eye view of Midvale works (Box 1, Folder 183)
  #1779Y
- Works from top of main Office building on Wissahickon Avenue, looking North - 1952 (Box 1, Folder 184)
  #1779Z
- Audrey Helen, IBM Dept., Main Office, early 1951 (Box 1, Folder 185)
  #1809
- Bricks on edge of mold? (Box 1, Folder 186)
  #1817C
- Placing bricks on edge of mold (Box 1, Folder 187)
  #1817A, B
- Joyce Anderson, Payroll Dept. - March 1951 (Box 1, Folder 188)
  #1818
- Ajax Furnace personnel - March 1951 (Box 1, Folder 189)
  #1819A
- Ajax furnace personnel - March 1951 (Box 1, Folder 190)
  #1819B
- Chipper - March, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 191)
  #1822
- Shoveling coal - July, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 192)
  #1830
- Locomotive crew - 1949 (Box 1, Folder 193)
  #1831
- Workers leaving Midvale Plant - July, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 194)
  #1833 -- 1 photograph
- Changing electrodes operators - Frank Crathy, John McHugh, McDonald - March, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 195)
  #1834
- Locomotive #47 moving ingots on flat car - November 28, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 196)
  #1844
- Reba Gantz, Payroll Dept. Main Office - December, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 197)
  #1850
- Elaine Regen, payroll Dept. Main Office - December, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 198)
  #1851
- Visit of Irish Trade Unionists - December 13, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 199)
  #1854
- Frank Caesario, Jr. - Observer using spethoscope to see steel color and gauge heat - June, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 200)
  #1884
- Diesel locomotive, #39 built by Whitecomb, January, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 201)
  #1872
- Midvale Locomotive #39 in steel yard (Box 1, Folder 202)
- Purchasing Dept. personnel, Main Office - 1952 (Box 1, Folder 203)
  #1885
- Employee Joseph O'Brien, checking plans - May 3, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 204)
  #1902
- Pouring low carbon stainless steel at electric furnace - 1949 (Box 1, Folder 205)
  #1903B
- Bricklayer working on oil heating furnace, #4 Maching Shop - May 31, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 206)
  #1903A
- Men loading locomotive tires at tire wharf - May 31, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 207)
  #1904
- Employees checking locomotive tires at shipping wharf - May 31, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 208)
  #1904C
- Employee Patrick Fitzgerald of the Diesel and Steam Repair Dept., cleaning locomotive #45 with steam Jenny and powered soap - May 31, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 209)
  #1905
- Women in Industrial Relations and Time Dept. Main Office - June 6, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 210)
  #1914
- Tracklayers laying track in Midvale Company Shipping Yard - 1949 (Box 1, Folder 211)
  #1917
- Cleaning in foundry; Taken for National Safety Council; and Midvale Safety Dept. - 1949 (Box 1, Folder 212)
  #1927C - 1 photograph
- Photographs in foundry and CP Annex, taken for National Safety Council and Midvale Safety Dept. - 1949 (Box 1, Folder 213)
  #1927D - 1 photograph
- Worker cleaning casting; taken for National Safety Council and Midvale Safety Dept. - 1949 (Box 1, Folder 214)
  #1927B - 1 photograph
- Foundry & CP Annex taken for NSC & Midvale Safety taken in 1949 (Box 1, Folder 215)
  #1927A
- Richard T. Nalle, President, Midvale Company. Office & Home, 1949 -- 1949 series of 1900's (Box 1, Folder 216)
  #1936
- Women Operators at payroll machine in Time Office - August 29, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 217)
  #1937
- 2 Zkonta negatives of picnic - July 16, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 218)
  #1950
- Press Plant - 1950 (Box 1, Folder 219)
  #1959
- Robert J. Chambers - Laborer-Former Roll Turner - 5/18/1950 (Box 1, Folder 220)
  #1962
- Photo of Helen Lesler - Showing methods of taking identification photographs of employees - 1950 (Box 1, Folder 221)
  #1963
- Loading gift baskets from Dept. 1887 - 1951 (Box 1, Folder 222)
  #2003
- Midvale Locomotive #42, moving lower crosshead beam.-April 16, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 223)
  #2020A - 1 photograph
- Locomotive #42 moving lower crosshead beam, April 16, 1954 -- April 16, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 224)
  #2020F - 1 photograph
- Locomotive #40 at Midvale (Box 1, Folder 225)
  #2022
- 2 men working at furnaces (Box 1, Folder 226)
  no neg. no. -- 1 photograph
- Pictures from Dr. Wrege - Rec'd. 7/15/2009 - All Midvale Steel (Box 2, Folder 1)
  7 photographs